Roger Steve Ruiz

+18045392255 hi@rog.gr http://rog.gr Richmond, VA

Profile

I'm a web developer with over five years experience building websites, interfaces, & products. From concept to execution, I'm interested in all aspects of user experience, interface design, & code optimizations. I've worked with JetBlue, Caesars Casinos, WellPoint, Chipotle, Condé Nast, & other clients. I have a proven background in successfully handling all aspects of web development.

Experience

FRONTEND ENGINEER, CO+LAB MULTIMEDIA; RICHMOND, VA - 2015 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CONDÉ NAST; NEW YORK, NY - 2013 - 2015

Building & maintaining a video streaming website along with nine other engineers.

Practicing SCRUM along with continuous integration & daily deployments to production.

Routine daily interactions with the director of product design. Working in a completely Rails 4 development environment. Working remotely four to five times per month.

SENIOR DEVELOPER, ROKKAN; NEW YORK, NY - 2011 - 2013

Worked collaboratively with UI & UX designers to execute websites for clients. Involved in client presentations and internal meetings throughout the process. Lead developer on JetBlue, Chipotle, & WellPoint projects. Gave talks and trained coworkers on new topics.

Education

Nassau Community College 2007 – A.A.S. Digital Art & Printing

Skills

HTML, CSS, Sass, Javascript, jQuery, Ember, Rails, Backbone, AMD, TDD, NodeJS, Grunt, Bash, Zsh, Git, SVN, /r[egx]{2,}p?/i, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

References available upon request